KARTIK SHAH

kartik.isworking@gmail.com | +61 404 874 569

https://ikartiks.github.io/ | https://github.com/ikartiks | https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks

Summary of Experience

I have 7.10 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. Looking for an opportunity at New South Wales, Australia (State sponsored PR holder).

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree, Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

Technical Skills

Strong: Android, Kotlin, BackBase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP, RXJava /RXKotlin,

observables

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM, Kanban boards.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

Work Experience -

Apr 2019 - Present, Frollo Sydney, Australia

- I work on an app for Volt bank, build on top of the Frollo SDK, so my major chunk of work here includes having an aesthetic UI.
- The app allows you to link your bank account, view your transactions, expenses set savings goals.
- I mainly work on the frontend of this application, although I have worked parts of the frollo SDK and app as well.

Jan 2019 – April 2019, Telstra via Luvo (contract). Sydney, Australia

• Working on Telstra's 24x7 app. I worked mainly on their messaging module, as well as redesigning the app modules.

Indian Experience - 6 years

OCT 2015 – OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.9 * rating.
- Built a hybrid app using phonegap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR

For complete Indian experience view detailed resume.

Major Projects

Frollo	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=us.frollo.frollo.prod	Kotlin, LiveData, TDD
Telstra 24x7	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.telstra.mobile.android.mytelstra	Kotlin, RxJava / RxKotlin, TDD
HDFC Bank	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.snapwork.hdfc	Android, Backbase, Kotlin
Vocabulary Flashcards	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Kotlin (my
		product)
YRD Health app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yrdtechnologies	Android, Kotlin (in beta request access)
EPMWare	http://epmware.com/	Spring, Hibernate, JPA, AngularJS
Dr. Fixit	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit	Hybrid app development
Team Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker	Android, Couch database
USL's RCB IPL Team	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android	Android, core JS, PHP
USL's Signature Selfies	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies	Android, core JS, PHP
app		
Britania's iHealthU	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge	Android, core JS, PHP
Adlabs Imagica	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark	Android, core JS, PHP
Castrol Cricket	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android	Android, core JS, PHP
EC Diwali cracker app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android	Android, core JS, PHP

Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.